Curriculum Vitae - Everton Canez F. da Silva

Everton Canez - everton.canez@gmail.com - Version 4.5, Oct 2019

About me

Flexible and competent easy going style, with 18y+ hands-on software development experience in web and mobile projects working in many teams for the public sector. I good communication skills and I'm a very committed self-learning person.

I like frontend and backend development, I love programming languages and I'm looki for new challenges. I'm a hard worker and I'm really committed person who likes to ge things well done.

I work as a frontend and backend developer with teams who provide software solution improve public services in mobile and web projects.

Full Stack Developer

Hotmedia - Web Broadcast Radio & Television

Sep 2019 – Present

♀ Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

- Backend development
- Frontend development
- Automation tests
- Software Architecture
- Automate builds and releases on GitLab
- Write documentation and blog out best practices

Full Stack Engineer / Developer

PROCERGS

Aug 2011 – Present

Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

- Create and maintain microservices JavaEE/NodeJS based for serving other software solutions in the company
- Part of the technical team which supports 200+ frontend developers
- Prospecting new technologies (R&D)
- Write documentation and blog out best practices
- Support teams to build delivery pipelines on Jenkins
- Automate builds and releases on Azure DevOps Server

Professional Experience

Computing Analyst

PROCERGS

Aug 2011 - Dec 2011 (4 months)

♀ Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

- Support development teams using Angular, Ionic Framework + Cordova
- Responsible for development and maintainability of microservices for the National Company
- Frontend delivery pipelines on Jenkins
- Responsible for development and maintainability of the Company's internal App St
- Mobile Development using Android

Web Developer

PROCERGS

february 2005 - August 2010 (5 years 7 months)

🕈 Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

- Java and Oracle Workflow development in several systems for the management are the company
- Development of Java Web services using SOAP for integration between several diffe systems
- Frontend development using JSF and other build in house Java Framework for inter

Technical Operations Engineer

PROCERGS

March 2000 - January 2005 (4 years 11 months)

♀ Porto Alegre Area, Brazil

- Responsible for developing web systems for the company's intranet
- Database modelling

- Shell and Batch scripts for the CA Workload software
- System's workflow planning

System Network Administrator

- Colégio Marista Nossa Senhora do Rosário
- **August** 1998 July 2001 (3 years)
- **♀** Porto Alegre Area, Brazil
 - Network administration
 - School's intranet and website development
 - IT Support

Education

2014 - 2016

Graduate Course Computer Software Engineering for Government Solutions Universidade de Santa Cruz do Sul

2007 - 2010

University Graduate Information Systems Technologist Faculdade de Tecnologia SENAC-RS

Main Interests

- Software Architecture
- Functional Programming
- OOP
- Angular
- Typescript
- NodeJS
- Open Source
- UX
- APIs
- Microservices
- Java

Soft Skills

- Committed
- Creative
- Passionate
- Proactive
- Productive
- Empathy
- Active listening
- Adaptable
- Business focused
- Enthusiastic
- Collaborative
- Organized

Personal Details

Nome: Everton Canez Ferreira da Silva

Location: Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Social Media: @notreniev, notreniev.github.com

Calendly https://calendly.com/evcanez

Skype: everton.canez@gmail.com

Phone: Phone: +55 51 991120621

Portfolio

Randonneurs Brazil

- <u>Randonneurs Manager Website:</u> This is a frontend for content administration of the MySQL database that serves data for Randonneurs App, Randonneurs Manager AF the website itself. It was written in **Angular 8** using **Bootstrap 4** styles and **NG Boot** (no JQuery).
- Randonneurs Manager API: **NodeJS** backend for serving data to a administration per for the Randonneurs Brazil website. It persists its data in a **MySQL** database and us Restify Framework to produce Restful structure.
- Randonneurs App API: This is another NodeJS backend persisting data in a MySQL database for Randonneurs Brazil, which is an organisation that regulates and appropriate Randonneurs Mondiaux, the BRMs, linked to the Audax Club Parisien of cylinks backend will serve data to an Angular 8 website and a React Native app.

BMMOB

• An App to help police from Rio Grande do Sul State to attend daily police reports. It written in **Ionic Framework** with **Cordova** to run in **Android** devices. This app communicates with a **Java** (1.8) backend on **JBoss Server 7.0** to synchronize its data several informations and photos of this reports with an **Oracle Database**.

National Address Consulting

• This is a microservice written in Java for integration with other Government application for consuming address in Brazil as a Java Rest API. It helps to locate address inform in the whole country based on zip code, address, city or state. This API was develop Java 1.8 running in a cluster of JBoss Server 6.4 and Oracle 10 Database.

PROCERGS Apps

 This is an internal app store for PROCERGS company to distribute apps for clients v doesn't want to distribute their apps through oficial app stores like Google or Apple was written using AngularJS in Front-end, communicating with Java 1.8 REST API or backend, and persisting its data in a PostgreSQL Database. Project in partnership with Pontifical Catholic University (PUCRS) and Huawei to informatize school classroom processes in public schools of State of Rio Grande dc Consists in synchronise classroom information through a mobile app running in an Android tablet and then sending all information to a JBoss server REST API in the backend with an Oracle Database.

Turismo RS

• This is an **Android** app for Tourism in the Rio Grande do Sul state. It gives informat about the cities, touristic points of interest, places to stay, places to eat, hotels and communicates with an PHP backend.

Offline ballot box

 The popular offline ballot box is an Android app that consists of an electronic ballo app to vote on citizen budget priorities, and it's persisted on a PHP backend API usi PostgreSQL. Its goal is to bring popular voting to areas without internet access, allo more citizens to participate on the voting process to prioritise projects on public se

Voice List

• This is an **Android** app briefly inspired by the GTD (Getting Things Done) concept. It personal project which allow users to create organised lists using their voice and m those lists to manage tasks, prioritising between active and archived lists and also marking list items as being finished.

52 Weeks Challenge

• This is also a personal project written in **Android** to help users to save money. The here is to save a small amount of money every week always doubling this small que each week until you get the amount you need to achieve your goals.

Technical Skills

Languages and Frameworks:

- JavaScript
- Typescript
- AngularJS
- Angular 2, 3, 4, 5...8
- Restify
- Express
- NodeJS
- UX
- Bootstrap
- Ionic Framework + Cordova
- Progressive Web Apps
- RESTful APIs
- Java
- Android
- OOP
- Microservices
- Spring Boot
- Shell script

Databases:

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB
- SQLite
- Oracle
- PostgreSQL

OS: OS X, Windows

Tools:

- VSCode
- Eclipse
- Git
- Bash Shell
- Gradle
- Netbeans
- Maven
- Hibernate
- Spring Tools Suite

- Jenkins
- Artifactory

Language Skills

Portuguese: Native language

• English: Fluent

Personal Interests

- My family: Father of a little girl and owned by two cats
- Music: Playing guitar, blues, rock, Eric Clapton, Led Zeppelin, AC/DC
- Movies: Star Wars, Indiana Jones, Back to the Future
- Books: Lord of The Rings by J.R.R. Tolkien, Eric Clapton Biography by Eric Clapton, L Zeppelin Biography by Mick Wall
- TV Shows: The Big Bang Theory, Stranger Things, Brooklin 99, La Casa de Papel
- Programming: Frontend, UX and Backend Development
- Sports: Running, bicycle, swimming

Timeline

1997	1998	2000	2001	2005	2011	2015 - present
HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML	HTML5	HTML5
CSS						
JavaScript						
	ASP 3.0	PHP	Java	Java	Java	Java
			PHP	JSP	JSP	Android
				PHP	PHP	lonic
					Android	Typescript
						Angular
						NodeJS

Version 4.5 Last update 2019-11-11 10:03 AM